export const quizQuestions = [
  {
    category: "variable",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "Which of the following is a valid variable name in Python?",
    options: ["2value", "value_2", "value-2", "value 2"],
    answer: "value_2",
  },
  {
    category: "variable",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "What is a correct way to declare a Python variable?",
    options: ["var name = Mary", "#name = Mary", "$name = Mary", "name = Mary"],
    answer: "name = Mary",
  },
  {
    category: "variable",
    kind: "fill",
    question: "Create a variable named x and assign the value 50 to it.",
    codeParts: ["", " = ", ""],
    answer: ["x", "50"],
  },
  {
    category: "datatype",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "What is the data type of x?\n\nx = 5.0",
    options: ["int", "str", "float", "bool"],
    answer: "float",
  },
  {
    category: "datatype",
    kind: "drag",
    question:
      "Select the correct functions to print the data type of a variable:",
    codeParts: ["", "("," ","(x))"],
    answer: ["print","type"],
    options: ["typ", "var", "echo"],
  },
  {
    category: "boolean",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "What will be the result of the following syntax: print(5 > 3)? ",
    options: ["True", "False", "5 > 3"],
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    category: "operator",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "What does the '%' operator do in Python?",
    options: ["Addition", "Division", "Modulo", "Exponentiation"],
    answer: "Modulo",
  },
  {
    category: "operator",
    kind: "fill",
    question: "Multiply 10 with 5, and print the result.",
    codeParts: ["print(10", "", "5)"],
    answer: ["*"],
  },
  {
    category: "list",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "What will be the result of the following syntax:  mylist = ['apple', 'banana', 'cherry']   print(mylist[1])",
    options: ["apple", "banana", "cherry"],
    answer: "banana",
  },
  {
    category: "set",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "Which one of these is a set?",
    options: ["myset = ('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')", "myset = ['apple', 'banana', 'cherry']", "myset = {'apple', 'banana', 'cherry'}"],
    answer: "myset = {'apple', 'banana', 'cherry'}",
  },
  {
    category: "set",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "Set items cannot be removed after the set has been created.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    category: "dict",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "Which one of these dictionary methods can be used to add items to a dictionary?",
    options: ["add( )", "insert( )","update( )"],
    answer: "update( )",
  },
  {
    category: "dict",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "What is a dictionary method for removing an item from a dictionary?",
    options: ["delete( )", "remove( )","pop( )"],
    answer: "pop( )",
  },
  {
    category: "function",
    kind: "multiple",
    question: "What is the correct keyword for defining functions in Python?",
    options: ["function", "func","def"],
    answer: "def",
  },
  
];
